Hi! My name is Paola, and I am a software engineer at Microsoft.
嗨！我的名字是保拉，我在微软的软件工程师。
Let's talk about how the internet works. My job relies on networks being able
让我们来谈谈互联网是如何工作的。我的工作依赖于网络能够
to talk with one another, but back in the 1970s there was no standard method for this.
彼此交谈，但早在20世纪70年代出现了这种没有标准的方法。
It took the work of Vint Cerf and Bob Kahn to invent the internet working protocol, to make communication possible.
花了温特·塞夫和鲍勃·卡恩的工作，发明了互联网的工作协议，使通信成为可能。
This invention laid the groundwork for what we now call the internet.
本发明奠定了我们现在所说的互联网的基础。
The internet is a network of networks. It links billions of devices together all
互联网是网络的网络。它把数十亿设备都在一起
around the globe. So maybe you're connected with a laptop or a phone through wifi, then
在全球范围内。因此，也许你正在使用一台笔记本电脑或通过WiFi手机连接，然后
that wifi connection connects to an internet service provider (or ISP), and that ISP connects
该无线连接连接到互联网服务提供商（ISP或），以及ISP所连接
you to billions and billions of devices around the world through hundreds of thousands of
你数十亿世界各地的装置，通过数十万
networks that are all interconnected.
网络，都是相互联系的。
One thing that most people do not appreciate is that the internet is really a design philosophy and an architecture expressed in a set of protocols.
大多数人不明白的一件事是，互联网是一个真正的设计理念，并在一组协议表示的架构。
A protocol is a well known set of rules and standards, that if all parties
协议是一个众所周知的规则和标准，如果各方
agree to use it, will allow them to communicate without trouble.
同意使用它，就会让他们无故障通信。
How the internet actually physically works is less important than the fact that this design philosophy
如何在互联网实际的物理作品比事实不那么重要了，这样的设计理念
has allowed the internet to adapt and absorb new communication technologies.
已经允许互联网来适应和吸收新的通信技术。
This is because in order for a new technology to use the internet in some fashion, it just needs to know which protocols to work with.
这是因为，为了使新技术使用互联网以某种方式，它只是需要知道哪些协议的工作。
All the different devices on the internet have unique addresses.
所有在互联网上的不同的设备有唯一的地址。
An address on the internet is just a number, similar to a phone number or a sort of street address,
在互联网上的地址只是一个数字，类似于电话号码或者某种街道地址，
that's unique to each computer or device at the edge of the network.
这是独特的，以在所述网络的边缘的每个计算机或设备。
This is similar to how most homes and businesses have a mailing address. You don't need to know a person to
这类似于大多数家庭和企业如何有一个邮件地址。你不需要知道一个人
send them a letter in the mail, but you do need to know their address and how to write
他们发送的邮件的信，但你需要知道他们的地址怎么写
the address properly so the letter can be carried by a mail system to its destination.
地址正确以致求信可以通过邮件系统进行到它的目的地。
The addressing system for computers on the internet is similar and it forms part of one
对于互联网上的计算机的地址系统是类似的，它形成一个组成部分
of the most important protocols used in internet communication simply called the internet protocol or IP.
在网络通信中使用的最重要的协议，简称为互联网协议或IP。
A computer's address then is called its IP address. Visiting a website is really
那么一台电脑的地址称为IP地址。访问一个网站真的
just your computer asking another computer for information. Your computer sends a message
只是你的电脑询问信息的另一台计算机。您的计算机发送消息
to the other computer's IP address and it also sends along its origin address, so the
到另一台计算机的IP地址，而且还沿着其源地址发送，所以
other computer knows where to send its response.
其他计算机知道在哪里发送它的响应。
You may have seen an IP address. It's just a bunch of numbers! These numbers are organized in a hierarchy. Just like a home address has
你可能已经看到了一个IP地址。它只是一串数字！这些数字在层级组织。就像一个家庭地址有
a country, a city, a street, and a house number, an IP address has many parts.
一个国家，一个城市，街道和门牌号码，IP地址有很多部分。
Just like all digital data, each of these numbers is represented in bits. Traditional IP addresses are 32 bits
就像所有的数字数据，这些数字的位表示。传统的IP地址是32位
long, with 8 bits for each part of the address.
长，具有为地址的各部分8位。
The earlier numbers usually identify the country and regional network of the device.
早期的数字通常标识国家和设备的区域网络。
Then come the subnetworks, and then finally the address
然后来的子网，最后地址
of the specific device. This version of IP addressing is called IPv4. It was designed
特定设备的。该IP的寻址版本被称为IPv4的。它被设计
in 1973 and was widely adopted in the early 80s, and provides for more than 4 billion unique addresses for devices connecting to the internet.
在1973年，并于80年代初被广泛采用，并提供超过4个十亿唯一的地址连接到互联网的设备。
But the internet has turned out to be much more popular than even Vint Cerf imagined and 4 billion unique addresses won't be enough.
但是，互联网已经被证明是更受欢迎的，甚至比温特·塞夫想象和4个十亿唯一的地址是不够的。
We're now in the middle of a multi-year transition to a longer IP address
我们现在正处在一个多一年过渡到较长的IP地址的中间
format called IPv6, which uses 128 bits per address and provides over 340 undecillion unique addresses.
格式称为IPv6，其采用128位地址每并提供超过340 undecillion唯一的地址。
That's more than enough for every grain of sand on Earth to have its own IP address.
这足以满足地球上每一粒沙子都拥有自己的IP地址了。
Most users never see or care about internet addresses.
大多数用户不会看到或关心的互联网地址。
A system called the domain name system or DNS associates names like www.example.com with the corresponding addresses.
系统称为域名系统或DNS与对应的地址相关联像www.example.com名。
Your computer uses the DNS to look up domain names and get the associated IP
您的计算机使用的DNS查找域名并获得相关的IP
address which is used to connect your computer to the destination on the internet.
它用于将计算机连接到互联网上的目的地地址。
And it goes a little something like this: (voice 1) "Hey, hi there, I want to go to www.code.org."
而且它会少了一些这样的：（1声）“喂，您好，我想去www.code.org。”
(voice 2) "Mm.. yeah I don't know the IP address for that domain let me ask around. Hey, do
（声音2）“嗯..是啊，我不知道该域的IP地址，让我问身边。哎，做
you know how to get to code.org?" (voice 3) "Yeah, I got it right here it's 174.129.14.120."
你知道怎么去Code.org透过？”（声音3）‘是啊，我就在这里它是174.129.14.120’。
(voice 2) "Oh okay, great, thanks. I'm gonna write that down and save it for later in case
（声音2）“哦，好，太好了，谢谢，我会记下来并保存，以便以后的情况下，
I need it again. Hey here's that address you wanted." (voice 1) "Awesome! Thank you."
我再需要它。嘿，这就是你想要的那个地址。“（声音1）”真棒！谢谢。”
So how do we design a system for billions of devices to find any one of billions of different websites?
那么，我们如何设计一个系统，数十亿的设备找到的数十亿个不同的网站中的任何一个？
There is no way one DNS server can handle all the requests from all devices.
有没有办法一台DNS服务器可以处理所有设备的所有要求。
The answer is that DNS servers are connected in a distributed hierarchy, and are divided
答案是DNS服务器连接在一个分布式的层次结构，并分为
into zones, splitting up responsibility for the major domains such as .org, .com, .net, etc.
进区，分手了责任的主要领域，如.ORG，.COM，.NET等。
DNS was originally created to be an open and public communication protocol for government
DNS最初创建成为政府的开放和公开的通信协议
and educational institutions. Because of its openness, DNS is susceptible to cyber attacks.
和教育机构。由于它的开放性，DNS容易受到网络攻击。
An example attack is DNS spoofing. That's when a hacker taps into a DNS server and changes
一个例子攻击DNS欺骗。这时候，一个黑客水龙头到DNS服务器和变化
it to match a domain name with the wrong IP address. This lets the attacker send people
它用错误的IP地址匹配的域名。这让攻击者发送人
to an imposter website. If this happens to you, you are vulnerable for more problems
对冒名顶替者的网站。如果您遇到这种情况，你很容易受到更多的问题
because you are using that fake website as if it's real.
因为您使用的是假网站，如果它是真实的。
The internet is huge and getting bigger everyday.
互联网是巨大的，每天越来越大。
But the domain name system and internet protocol are designed to scale,
但域名系统和互联网协议的设计规模，
no matter how much the internet grows.
无论互联网有多大的增长。